Construction Photographs of the Golden Gate Bridge, 1933-1934
The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley
Construction Photographs of the Golden Gate Bridge.
BANC PIC 1905.14251-.14284--PIC
1,066 photographic prints, black and white; 13 x 19 cm. 373 digital objects
The Bancroft Library. University of California, Berkeley. Berkeley, California 94720-6000
Information for Researchers
Access
Collection is available for use
Digital Representations Available
Digital representations of selected original pictorial materials are available in the list of materials below. Digital image files were prepared from selected Library originals by the Library Photographic Service. Library originals were copied onto 35mm color transparency film; the film was scanned and transferred to Kodak Photo CD (by Custom Process); and the Photo CD files were color-corrected and saved in JFIF (JPEG) format for use as viewing files.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Gift of Professor Keim, 1955.
Background
The Golden Gate Bridge is a steel suspension bridge for vehicles and pedestrians extending from Fort Point in San Francisco to Marin County over the San Francisco Bay. Its central span is 4,200 feet long and its 746-feet towers are the largest ever built. The bridge was erected under the direction and plans of Joseph B. Strauss and opened in 1937.
(Source: Hart, James D. A Companion to California. New York, Oxford University Press, 1978.)
Scope and Content
The Golden Gate Bridge construction photographs were taken between 1933 and 1934. Some of the 2,054 photographs are stamped "Gabriel Moulin Photo." The other photographers are unknown. The collection is a thorough documentation of every phase of construction of the bridge, including excavation of sites, and building of the various components, such as access trestles, caissons, abutments, anchorages, pylons, floor structures, approach spans, piers, towers, portals, viaducts, tunnels, and the toll plaza. Many views show men at work, and the tools and equipment being used. Vantage points vary from the bridge structures, from the water, Marin, San Francisco, and Sausalito.
The collection is arranged by subject. Each subject is treated as a series and given a consecutive call number in the range 1905.14251-.14284. The finding aid notes the series titles and number of photographs in each series.
Container Listing
- 1905.14251 no. 1-13, Access Trestle
  - Access Trestle
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
- 1905.14252 no. 1-5, Alameda Storage Yard, McClintick Marshall
  - Alameda Storage Yard, McClintick Marshall
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
- 1905.14253 no. 1-100, Cable Spinning
  - Cable Spinning
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
  - Cable Spinning
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
    - 60
    - 61
    - 62
    - 63
    - 64
    - 65
  - Cable Spinning
    - 66
    - 67
    - 68
    - 69
    - 70
    - 71
    - 72
    - 73
    - 74
    - 75
    - 76
    - 77
    - 78
    - 79
    - 80
    - 81
    - 82
    - 83
    - 84
    - 85
    - 86
    - 87
    - 88
    - 89
    - 90
    - 91
    - 92
    - 93
    - 94
    - 95
    - 96
    - 97
    - 98
    - 99
    - 100
- 1905.14254 no. 1-3, Caisson, San Francisco Pier
  - Caisson, San Francisco Pier
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
- 1905.14255 no. 1-24, Marin Abutment Excavation
  - Marin Abutment Excavation
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
- 1905.14256 no. 1-102, Marin Anchorage
  - Marin Anchorage
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
  - Marin Anchorage
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
    - 60
    - 61
    - 62
    - 63
    - 64
    - 65
  - Marin Anchorage
    - 66
    - 67
    - 68
    - 69
    - 70
    - 71
    - 72
    - 73
    - 74
    - 75
    - 76
    - 77
    - 78
    - 79
    - 80
    - 81
    - 82
    - 83
    - 84
    - 85
    - 86
    - 87
    - 88
    - 89
    - 90
    - 91
    - 92
    - 93
    - 94
    - 95
    - 96
    - 97
    - 98
    - 99
    - 100
    - 101
    - 102
- 1905.14257 no. 1-19, Marin Anchorage and Pylon N-1
  - Marin Anchorage and Pylon N-1
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
- 1905.14258 no. 1-56, Floor Structures
  - Floor Structures
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
  - Floor Structures
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
- 1905.14259 no. 1-19, Marin Approach Spans
  - Marin Approach Spans
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
- 1905.14260 no. 1-2, Marin Daylighting
  - Marin Daylighting
    - 1
    - 2
- 1905.14261 no. 1-114, Marin Pier and Tower
  - Marin Pier and Tower
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
  - Marin Pier and Tower
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
    - 60
    - 61
    - 62
    - 63
    - 64
    - 65
    - 66
    - 67
    - 68
    - 69
    - 70
    - 71
    - 72
    - 73
    - 74
    - 75
  - Marin Pier and Tower
    - 76
    - 77
    - 78
    - 79
    - 80
    - 81
    - 82
    - 83
    - 84
    - 85
    - 86
    - 87
    - 88
    - 89
    - 90
    - 91
    - 92
    - 93
    - 94
    - 95
    - 96
    - 97
    - 98
  - Marin Pier and Tower
    - 99
    - 100
    - 101
    - 102
    - 103
    - 104
    - 105
    - 106
    - 107
    - 108
    - 109
    - 110
    - 111
    - 112
    - 113
    - 114
- 1905.14262 no. 1-8, Marin Tower and Pylon S-1
  - Marin Tower and Pylon S-1
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
- 1905.14263 no. 1-59, Miscellaneous Views
  - Miscellaneous Views
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
  - Miscellaneous Views
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
- 1905.14264 no. 1-38, North Approach Spans
  - North Approach Spans
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
  - North Approach Spans
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
  - North Approach Spans
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
- 1905.14265 no. 1, Paint Panels
  - Paint Panels, 1
- 1905.14266 no. 1-3, Personnel
  - Personnel
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
- 1905.14267 no. 1, Portal Closure
  - Portal Closure, 1
- 1905.14268 no. 1-5, Presidio Road
  - Presidio Road
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
- 1905.14269 no. 1-25, Pylon N-1
  - Pylon N-1
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
  - Pylon N-1
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
- 1905.14270 no. 1-49, Pylon S-1
  - Pylon S-1
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
  - Pylon S-1
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
- 1905.14271 no. 1-4, Saddle Details
  - Saddle Details
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
- 1905.14272 no. 1-2, Sausalito Lateral
  - Sausalito Lateral
    - 1
    - 2
- 1905.14273 no. 1-165, San Francisco Anchorage
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
    - 60
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 61
    - 62
    - 63
    - 64
    - 65
    - 66
    - 67
    - 68
    - 69
    - 70
    - 71
    - 72
    - 73
    - 74
    - 75
    - 76
    - 77
    - 78
    - 79
    - 80
    - 81
    - 82
    - 83
    - 84
    - 85
    - 86
    - 87
    - 88
    - 89
    - 90
    - 91
    - 92
    - 93
    - 94
    - 95
    - 96
    - 97
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 98
    - 99
    - 100
    - 101
    - 102
    - 103
    - 104
    - 105
    - 106
    - 107
    - 108
    - 109
    - 110
    - 111
    - 112
    - 113
    - 114
    - 115
    - 116
    - 117
    - 118
    - 119
    - 120
    - 121
    - 122
    - 123
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 124
    - 125
    - 126
    - 127
    - 128
    - 129
    - 130
    - 131
    - 132
    - 133
    - 134
    - 135
    - 136
    - 137
    - 138
    - 139
    - 140
    - 141
    - 142
    - 143
    - 144
    - 145
  - San Francisco Anchorage
    - 146
    - 147
    - 148
    - 149
    - 150
    - 151
    - 152
    - 153
    - 154
    - 155
    - 156
    - 157
    - 158
    - 159
    - 160
    - 161
    - 162
    - 163
    - 164
    - 165
- 1905.14274 no. 1-24, San Francisco Anchorage and Pylon S-1
  - San Francisco Anchorage and Pylon S-1
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
- 1905.14275 no. 1-14, San Francisco Anchorage and Pylon S-2
  - San Francisco Anchorage and Pylon S-2
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
- 1905.14276 no. 1-4, San Francisco Approach Spans
  - San Francisco Approach Spans
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
- 1905.14277 no. 1-81, San Francisco Pier
  - San Francisco Pier
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
  - San Francisco Pier
    - 29
    - 30
    - 31
    - 32
    - 33
    - 34
    - 35
    - 36
    - 37
    - 38
    - 39
    - 40
    - 41
    - 42
    - 43
    - 44
    - 45
    - 46
    - 47
    - 48
    - 49
    - 50
    - 51
    - 52
    - 53
    - 54
    - 55
    - 56
    - 57
    - 58
    - 59
    - 60
    - 61
    - 62
    - 63
    - 64
    - 65
    - 66
    - 67
    - 68
    - 69
    - 70
    - 71
    - 72
    - 73
    - 74
    - 75
    - 76
    - 77
    - 78
    - 79
    - 80
    - 81
- 1905.14278 no. 1-26, South Steel Approach Spans
  - South Steel Approach Spans
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
  - South Steel Approach Spans
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
- 1905.14279 no. 1, Toll Plaza
  - Toll Plaza, 1
- 1905.14280 no. 1-28, San Francisco Tower
  - San Francisco Tower
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
  - San Francisco Tower
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
- 1905.14281 no. 1-31, Viaduct, High Presidio Approach
  - Viaduct, High Presidio Approach
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
  - Viaduct, High Presidio Approach
    - 20
    - 21
    - 22
    - 23
    - 24
    - 25
    - 26
    - 27
    - 28
    - 29
    - 30
    - 31
- 1905.14282 no. 1-21, Viaduct, Low Presidio Approach
  - Viaduct, Low Presidio Approach
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
    - 12
    - 13
    - 14
    - 15
    - 16
    - 17
    - 18
    - 19
    - 20
    - 21
- 1905.14283 no. 1-11, Waldo Tunnel
  - Waldo Tunnel
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8
    - 9
    - 10
    - 11
- 1905.14284 no. 1-8, Wing Wall of Sausalito Lateral
  - Wing Wall of Sausalito Lateral
    - 1
    - 2
    - 3
    - 4
    - 5
    - 6
    - 7
    - 8